New York Grape Country Cooperative records, 1985-1988
New York Grape Country Cooperative records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York Grape Country Cooperative records, 1985-1988
6709
New York Grape Country Cooperative
2.4 cubic ft
Correspondence, Financial Records, Legal Documents, Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ephemera, correspondence, and financial records and industry related material.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
New York Grape Country Co-Op was incorporated into produce and market vinefresh, the pink grape juice made from wine grapes grown in New York State, primarily in the Finger Lakes region.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records document the production, marketing, and sale of Vinefresh, the pink grape juice, through board records, reports, correspondence, production and sales ledgers and promotional materials.
SUBJECTS
Subjects:
Grape industry New York (State); Grape juice industry New York (State); Grape juice.; Grape juice United States
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Box 3 contains restricted material. Some folders restricted until 2025, 2026, 2035, and 2055.
CONTAINER LIST
- General ledger, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General ledgers, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Balance sheets, ledgers, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Balance sheets, ledgers, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Auditor's report, March 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Administrative documents, bylaws, incorporation, trademark, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Board meeting materials, May 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Board meeting agendas, October 1985 - March 31, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Board meeting minutes, October 1985 - March 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Annual meetings, October 1985 - May 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Board of directors, October 1985 - May 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- General journal, ledger, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Marketing and press releases for Vinefresh, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Vinefresh report to the board of directors, April 30, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Chronology file, September - December 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Chronology file, January - April 1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Chronology file, May - August 1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Chronology file, September - December 1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Chronology file, January - May 1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Chronology file, June 1987 - June 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Expense statements for Vinefresh tastings, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Marketing survey interviews 1, September 1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Marketing survey interviews 2, September 1985 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Tastings info sheets, expense forms (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Grape crop grower information, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Grape crop grower information, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Outgoing grower correspondence, August 1985 - May 1986 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Grower forms, marketing agreement, inspection certificate, various (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Survey of growers, re: Taylor grape purchase price, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Crown Harvest Jubilee, Watertown, NY, October 1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- New York Fresh Fruit and Vegetable Promotion Day, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Buckwheat Festival, Penn Yan, NY, September 1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Empire Farm Days, August 1986 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- New York State Fair exhibition, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Rochester Red Wings baseball program, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- School grape juice distribution, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Tourist geape juice distribution, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Radio and media lists for promotions, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Public tastings - various, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Markets - farms, roadside - survey and contacts, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Sales by customer and month, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Vinefresh product fact sheets, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Vinefresh price schedules, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Invoices - chronologic file, October 1985 - July 1986 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Invoices - chronologic file, August 1986 - October 1987 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Retailer correspondence, agreements, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Food broker information, Bratt-Foster Inc., RSL Associates Inc., others., 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- International Paper Company, packaging samples (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Administrative reports, meeting documents, bylaws, voting, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Acitivity and administrative notebook, March-November 1986 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- New York Association of Wine Producers, May 1986 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Shareholder list, February 2, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Annual meeting proxy votes., May 21, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Stock certificates, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- John Martini expenses (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Beverly Stamp expenses (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Grower hauling expenses (Box 2, Folder 3)
- AT&T Information Systems (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Beaumont & Stork Inc. - Insurance polcy (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Bercon Packaging Inc. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Bond Queen City (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Canandaigua Wine Company (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Central Marketing Equipment Corporation (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Charles S. Chadwick Public Relations (Box 2, Folder 10)
- New York Farm Bureau (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Gould & Swanson - NYGCC financial statements (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Gould & Swanson - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Frank L. Haveron Company Inc. - Food brokers (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Hogan-Souhan Dairy, Berry Good Inc. - Grape juice bottling (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Horwitz Paper and Packaging Company Inc. - plastic cups (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Ketchum Public Relations - marketing materials, brochures (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Long's Cards & Books - Office supplies (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Longview Fibre Company (Box 2, Folder 19)
- New York Wine and Grape Foundation (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Sayles, Evans, Braryton, Palmer, and Tifft Attorneys at Law- Edward B. Hoffman (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Stoda Corporation (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Syracuse Label Company Inc. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Taylor Wine Company - Juice sale (Box 2, Folder 24)
- The New Perceptions Team (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Tillman Press Inc. (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Trucking costs (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Earl T. Wadhams Inc. (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Watkins Glen International - race track (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Weyerhaeuser Paper Company (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Widmer Wine Cellars (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Williams, Stevens, McCarville, and Frizzel Attorneys at Lawl (Box 2, Folder 32)
- WHEC - TV (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Wolff Associates Inc. - Marketing (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Vendors, bills paid, misc. (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Accounting (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Sulfites (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Customer letters (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Cost and pricing (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Pink juice misc. (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Consumer questionaire (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Juice research (Box 2, Folder 42)
- New brochure (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Marketing research (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Vinefresh juice (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Grapes nutritional information (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Vinefresh logos (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Market survey (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Vinefresh press releases (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Manhattan juice tastings (Box 2, Folder 50)
- In store tastings (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Packing ideas (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Recipes, consumer information, mailing labels (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Finger Lakes Finest pink grape juice (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Vinefresh product labels, proofs (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Vinefresh product information, brochure, press clippings (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Vinefresh product kit (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Vinefresh radio jingle (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Sales projections (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Consumer surveys (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Promotions - includes WXXI, PBS (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Vinefresh blending, formulation, recipe (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Food shows (Box 2, Folder 63)
- November wine month juice tastings - Televison station promotions (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Rubber stamps (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Twenty year revolving-fund certificates, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Grower information, grower payment schedule, prices paid per ton, vineyard gallonage, NYAWP dues (Box 3)
  Restricted until 2025 or permission of archivist.
- New York State Grape Growers VineFresh Grape Juice :30 second television advertisement, VHS, April 9, 1986; V-843